<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Cloistered Monkey (Posts about printer)</title><link>https://necromuralist.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://necromuralist.github.io/categories/printer.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2023 &lt;a href="mailto:cloisteredmonkey.jmark@slmail.me"&gt;Cloistered Monkey&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 00:33:49 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Ubuntu 16.04 and the Brother HL-2140 Printer</title><link>https://necromuralist.github.io/posts/ubuntu-1604-and-the-brother-hl-2140-printer/</link><dc:creator>Cloistered Monkey</dc:creator><description>&lt;div id="outline-container-org2cdc1c4" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org2cdc1c4"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org2cdc1c4"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I (relatively) recently bought a &lt;a href="https://zareason.com/Limbo-560.html"&gt;ZaReason Limbo Desktop PC&lt;/a&gt; which comes with Ubuntu 16.04. I'm debating whether to update it to 16.10, given that updating broke the USB WiFi adapter I had on my older computer (the USB is recognized but not the WiFi adapter), but, in any case, I wanted to print something using my new computer today and ran into the same problem that I had when I updated my old computer to Ubuntu 14.10 - the default printer driver printed out a bunch of blank pages rather than the page I wanted to print. The last time I solved it by choosing a different model (the &lt;i&gt;HL-2142&lt;/i&gt;) but this time out I found a &lt;a href="http://ubuntuforums.org/showthread.php?t=2231405"&gt;stack overflow post&lt;/a&gt; that suggested using the &lt;b&gt;Brother HL-2140 Foomatic/hl1250 [en]&lt;/b&gt; driver instead. I tried it and it worked for me, so here goes.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-orgdef8fb3" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="orgdef8fb3"&gt;How To Choose the Correct Printer Driver&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-orgdef8fb3"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
First, open &lt;i&gt;Dash&lt;/i&gt; (the windows-key launches it on my keyboard), type in &lt;i&gt;Printers&lt;/i&gt; and click on the icon.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src="https://necromuralist.github.io/posts/ubuntu-1604-and-the-brother-hl-2140-printer/dash.png" alt="nil"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
This brings up the &lt;i&gt;printers&lt;/i&gt; dialog. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src="https://necromuralist.github.io/posts/ubuntu-1604-and-the-brother-hl-2140-printer/printers.png" alt="nil"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Double-click on the &lt;i&gt;HL-2140-series&lt;/i&gt; icon to bring up the &lt;i&gt;Printer Properties&lt;/i&gt; dialog.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src="https://necromuralist.github.io/posts/ubuntu-1604-and-the-brother-hl-2140-printer/printer_properties.png" alt="nil"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Click on the &lt;i&gt;Make and Model&lt;/i&gt; "Change" button (the fourth row). Let the program find the drivers and it will bring up the &lt;i&gt;Choose Driver&lt;/i&gt; dialog.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src="https://necromuralist.github.io/posts/ubuntu-1604-and-the-brother-hl-2140-printer/choose_driver.png" alt="nil"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Use the &lt;i&gt;Brother (recommended)&lt;/i&gt; option (it should already be selected) and click on the "Forward" button. This brings up the &lt;i&gt;Change Driver&lt;/i&gt; dialog with the &lt;i&gt;postscript&lt;/i&gt; driver chosen (which is the one that does not work for me).
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src="https://necromuralist.github.io/posts/ubuntu-1604-and-the-brother-hl-2140-printer/change_driver.png" alt="nil"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Select the &lt;i&gt;hl1250&lt;/i&gt; driver (by clicking on it) and click on the "Forward" button.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src="https://necromuralist.github.io/posts/ubuntu-1604-and-the-brother-hl-2140-printer/select_driver.png" alt="nil"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
This will bring up the &lt;i&gt;Existing Settings&lt;/i&gt; dialog. I've tried different options and haven't noticed a difference so I just leave it at whatever the default option is and click "Apply".
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src="https://necromuralist.github.io/posts/ubuntu-1604-and-the-brother-hl-2140-printer/existing_settings.png" alt="nil"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
At this point your driver should be updated so click on the "OK" button.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src="https://necromuralist.github.io/posts/ubuntu-1604-and-the-brother-hl-2140-printer/click_okay.png" alt="nil"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
If your experience is the same as mine, you will be able to print your documents at this point.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org2cb4129" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org2cb4129"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org2cb4129"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The basic method to get the &lt;i&gt;Brother HL-2140&lt;/i&gt; to print in Ubuntu 16.04 is to select the &lt;i&gt;hl1250&lt;/i&gt; driver instead of the default. Since I only do this when I need to set up a new computer, I alway have to do some googling to remember what to do, so hopefully this will help me save some searching if I ever have to do this again.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>printer</category><category>ubuntu</category><guid>https://necromuralist.github.io/posts/ubuntu-1604-and-the-brother-hl-2140-printer/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2017 23:55:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Ubuntu 14.10 and the Brother HL-2140</title><link>https://necromuralist.github.io/posts/201503ubuntu-1410-and-brother-hl-2140/</link><dc:creator>Cloistered Monkey</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I have a &lt;a href="http://www.brother-usa.com/Printer/ModelDetail/1/hl2140/Overview"&gt;Brother HL-2140 Laser Printer&lt;/a&gt; which was working previously but for some reason gave me a CUPs error when I tried to print today (I think this was the first time I'd tried to print since upgrading to Ubuntu 14.10). I searched for the error on the web and found this &lt;a href="http://ubuntuforums.org/showthread.php?t=1748457"&gt;forum post&lt;/a&gt; that didn't address my problem directly but did address a problem I had when I set up my printer before (on Ubuntu 14.04 - I'm using 14.10 now) where the printer would churn out blank pages instead of printing what I wanted so I decided to give it a try again. There are a few suggestions on the page but the two I tried both suggested using a different driver.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The first suggestion I tried was to use the &lt;i&gt;HL-2170&lt;/i&gt; instead of the/HL-2140./ This worked when I printed the first test page but after that it just silently failed no matter what I tried to install.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The next suggestion I tried was to use the &lt;i&gt;Brother HL-2140 Foomatic/hpijs-pcl5e&lt;/i&gt; driver. This didn't print any pages for me and gave a &lt;code&gt;Idle - filter failed&lt;/code&gt; error in the printer properties dialogue
box. I don't know what the message means, but since I fixed it without knowing, I guess I don't need to know.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Sandwiched between the &lt;i&gt;HL-2170&lt;/i&gt; and the &lt;i&gt;HL-2140&lt;/i&gt; models in the list of available drivers was the &lt;i&gt;HL-2142&lt;/i&gt; model. Since it seemed close enough to the 2140 (only off by two) I decided to try it and for whatever reason it worked. I'm pretty sure I used one of drivers the forum post suggested when I was using 14.04 (and the default &lt;i&gt;HL-2140&lt;/i&gt; driver before that) but something seems to have changed again.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
There's two lessons here:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  1. Use the &lt;i&gt;HL-2142&lt;/i&gt; driver for the &lt;i&gt;Brother HL-2140&lt;/i&gt; printer on Ubuntu 14.10
  2. Try drivers for similar models if you upgrade your Ubuntu installation and the printer stops working
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>brother</category><category>printer</category><category>ubuntu</category><guid>https://necromuralist.github.io/posts/201503ubuntu-1410-and-brother-hl-2140/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2015 06:53:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>